<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<opml version="1.0">
<body>
<outline text="Statement of the Issues Presented" _note="Whether a reasonable employer would believe that an employee has a serious medical condition for the purposes of 29 C.F.R. § 825.303 when the employee asks for an extended period of time off.&#10;&#10;Whether less than 24 hours notice is sufficient for a request for unforeseeable FMLA leave under 29 C.F.R. § 825.303 when the employee knew sooner than that that she was unable to work.&#10;"></outline>
<outline text="Statement of the Case" _note="Ms. Park alleges that Drummond Bioprocesses interfered with her right to take medical leave under the Family Medical Leave Act (FMLA). She contends her communication with her supervisor was sufficient to notify Drummond of her intent to take such leave. Ms. Park further contends that her supervisor's response to her communication amounted to a grant of FMLA leave. &#10;    District Court agreed with Drummond that Ms. Park failed to prove that she gave notice of her intent to take FMLA leave. Since there is no dispute as to the facts on record, and those facts are insufficient to show Ms. Park gave notice, the court below determined that Drummond was entitled to summary judgment on the matter.&#10;"></outline>
<outline text="Statement of Facts" _note="Ms. Park was a senior lab technician at Drummond Bioprocesses, and a valued member of their research staff. R. at 8. Drummond researches medicines for illnesses that often attack patients who are already sick with cystic fibrosis. *Id.* at 7. It was at a crucial moment in an important clinical trial of one of these treatments that Ms. Park stopped coming to work. R. at 14; *see also* R. at 10 (on the importance of the stage of the trial). In so doing, she set the trial back a whole year. R. at 10. This setback jeopardized the funding of the trial. *Id.* It also delayed the availability of an important treatment that would have lengthened lives and improved the quality of life for some very sick people. *Id.*&#10;&#10;When her brother died, Ms. Park took a week of bereavement leave. *Id.* at 14. While she was away, the team struggled to follow the rigorous experimental protocol. *Id.* at 10. During her leave, Ms. Park also struggled, though about whether she would be able to perform her duties on her return. *Id.* When she returned, Ms. Park had trouble concentrating on even the minor tasks she was performing during her first three days back. *Id.* When she resumed her normal, more rigorous, duties at the start of the following week, she had an even harder time, suffering flashbacks and insomnia. *Id.* As one might expect, given the focus this work demanded and her trouble the prior week, Ms. Park was unable to giver her work the attention it demanded. *Id.*&#10;&#10;Despite Ms. Park's, apprehension about returning to work, her struggle to focus even while on light duty during her first few days back, and her admitted failure to adequately conduct herself during the first day of more rigorous work, she did not communicate any of this difficulty to anyone until after the close of business on the following day, when she emailed her supervisor, Dr. Emerson. *Id.* In this email, she told him some of what she was going through and that she was not coming to work for a few weeks. *Id.* at 18. Dr. Emerson replied the following morning that he understood that she was going through a difficult time, asked if she had a therapist to talk to, and asked her to &quot;[k]eep [him] posted.&quot; *Id.* Over 36 hours later, Ms. Park finally replied to Dr. Emerson to tell him that she had a doctor's appointment coming up in five days. *Id.* She did not contact anyone from Drummond during those five days, nor did she follow up after her appointment. *Id.* at 15. When three days had gone by after the appointment, Drummond had to let Ms. Park go in order to salvage the project and its funding. *Id.* at 10.&#10;"></outline>
<outline text="Summary of the Argument" _note="Drummond contends that Ms. Park's communication was insufficient in content and and inadequately timed, and so did not constitute valid notice of intent to take FMLA leave. Finally, Drummond contends that, if Ms. Park did request FMLA leave, her supervisor did not grant it.&#10;"></outline>
<outline text="Argument" _note=""><outline text="Park did not provide adequate notice of her intent to take FMLA-qualifying leave." _note=""><outline text="Content: Park's email to Desmond was not adequate to notify him of her intent to take FMLA leave." _note=""></outline>
<outline text="Park's notice was not sufficient to make a reasonable employer understand that she had a serious health condition" _note=""><outline text="Brenneman: test for sufficiency of notice--was it reasonably adequate such that employer would know the employee had a serious health condition" _note="* &quot;the critical test for substantively-sufficient notice is whether the information that the employee conveyed to the employer was reasonably adequate to apprise the employer of the employee's request to take leave for a serious health condition that rendered him unable to perform his job.&quot;&#10;"><outline text="Define &quot;Serious health condition&quot; § 825.113 (a)" _note="* &quot;For purposes of FMLA, 'serious health condition' entitling an employee to FMLA leave means an illness, injury, impairment or physical or mental condition that involves inpatient care as defined in § 825.114 or continuing treatment by a health care provider as defined in § 825.115&quot;&#10;"></outline>
</outline>
<outline text="Hammon" _note="* Pilot developed an anxiety disorder. He had multiple conversations with his supervisor in which he complained of his symptoms &amp; that he was considering resigning since he felt like he could no longer do the job. The supervisor told him to take a couple of days off to get his confidence back. *Hammon* at 451.&#10;    * The 6th circuit ct. app. did not think that conversation contained enough information for the employer-defendant to reasonably conclude that employee-plaintiff's obvious emotional trouble constituted a serious medical condition.&#10;    * The only real difference between that scenario &amp; Park's is that Park mentioned that she planned to see a doctor. However, that by itself can be interpreted in a number of ways.&#10;    * O'Connor v. Busch shows that courts in this circuit applying Brenneman and Walton don't think that stating intent to see a doctor is sufficient to turn a request for time off to notice of a serious medical condition.&#10;&#10;Given the tragedy in Ms. Park's family, of course her supervisor understood that she was having a hard time. When he replied to her email, he told her he understood what she was going through. And then he did what any compassionate person would do, which is to make sure she had someone to talk to. And he asked her to check back in with him so he would know how she was doing.&#10;"></outline>
</outline>
<outline text="ALTERNATIVE: Park did not meet her obligation to provide certification of her condition at her employer's request." _note=""><outline text="Assume Park gave notice of her serious heath condition" _note="* Emerson asked if Park had been to see a Dr. and told her to keep him posted.&#10;"></outline>
</outline>
</outline>
<outline text="Timing: &lt;24 hours notice was inadequate for a condition that had been ongoing for weeks." _note=""><outline text="Standard: &quot;As soon as practicable,&quot; 29 C.F.R. § 825.303(a)" _note="* The notice Park actually gave was less than 24 hours&#10;* She was back at work for four days before leaving again, the last two of which involved the kind of work she claimed to be unable to perform.&#10; * When Park came back after her bereavement leave, she already had trouble concentrating despite the fact that the work she was doing at that point wasn't very hard. She should have known at that point that she would've been unable to do the much more demanding work that would be starting back up the following week.&#10;  * If she had found after the first Monday back, or even the following morning (since she claims that insomnia was part of the problem), that she couldn't work, that may have been enough time to let Callie Greene know she would have to work an additional shift or to come up with another staffing solution.&#10;"></outline>
<outline text="Cavin: “[w]hat is practicable, both in terms of the timing of the notice and its content, will depend upon the facts and circumstances of each individual case.”" _note="* The plaintiff in Cavin, was injured in a motorcycle accident. In that case, same-day notice was adequate given the acute nature of the injury.&#10;* In this case, the &quot;injury&quot; happened weeks before she gave notice&#10;&#10;Despite this difficulty, she did not communicate with her supervisor or anyone else to let them know she was having trouble so they could start figuring out a plan for staffing. When she resumed her normal, more rigorous, duties at the start of the following week, and she had an even harder time, she still failed to alert anyone to her difficulties. She again failed to ask for help on the next day of that week, after she failed to get any sleep the night before. Instead, she waited until after close of business on the last day she intended to work and sent an email to let her supervisor know she was not going to be coming in for a few weeks starting the very next day. Because it was an email, nobody was likely to or indeed did see it until the next day.&#10;&#10;Given the tragedy in Ms. Park's family, of course her supervisor understood that she was having a hard time. When he replied to her email, he told her he understood what she was going through. And then he did what any compassionate person would do, which is to make sure she had someone to talk to. And he asked her to check back in with him so he would know how she was doing.&#10;&#10;But she didn't check in. She didn't check in at all in the 5 days between her last email to her supervisor and her Dr's appointment. And when three days had gone by after that appointment, and Ms. Park still hadn't made any effort to update her supervisor, with the trial already ruined, Drummond had to let her go.&#10;"></outline>
</outline>
</outline>
<outline text="Conclusion" _note="Park's notice was not sufficient to entitle her to FMLA leave. It was not adequate to make her employer think she had a serious health condition. Even if it was adequate with regard to its content, the timing of the notice was not practicable. As a result, taxpayer money was wasted and very sick people were denied treatments that could have lengthened and improved their lives. While the tragedy she suffered was undeniably horrific, it does not absolve her of her responsibility to her employer, or to the people her work could have helped.&#10;"></outline>
</body>
</opml>